Baptiste Pesquet

Software engineer | Teacher | Trainer in computer science and artificial intelligence Bordeaux, FR

pesquet bpesquet

I teach computer science and artificial intelligence to students and professionals since 2006. Before that, I graduated as an engineer and worked for several years in the software industry. I try my best to combine a high level of technical expertise with the pedagogical qualities needed to deliver an efficient and enjoyable learning experience.

SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE (3)

Full-time professor at ENSC - Bordeaux INP

Teaching, course design, educational support, project and exam management.

Sep 2016 - Current

- Co-creator and head of the AI specialization track since 2019.
- Responsible for the second year of study and several CS and Al courses.
- Involved in training programs for external students and professionals.

Full-time professor at BTS IG/SIO, Chalon-sur-Saône, Laval, Lyon Teaching, educational support, exam management.

Sep 2006 - Aug 2016

- Member of the jury for the CAPET national teaching exam from 2016 to 2019.
- Passed the CAPET (2006) and Agrégation (2008, ranked first) national teaching exams.

Software Engineer at Artal, Toulouse

Sep 1999 - Aug 2006

Developer, tech lead and project lead for companies such as Airbus, Astrium and Alcatel.

EDUCATION (2)

Computer Science Engineer at ENSIIE, Evry

1996 - 1999

Graduate engineering school, majors in object-oriented programming and artificial intelligence.

CPGE Student at Lycée Pierre Corneille, Rouen

1994 - 1996

Classes Préparatoires aux Grandes Ecoles, option M.